[音樂]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克羅克福德：這是下一個問題。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Here's the next problem.
這一次會有一點不同，因為我們要做的是
This one's going to be a little bit different in that we're going to do it
總而言之，好嗎？
altogether, okay?
所以我們要用get方法建立一個數組包裝物件，
So we're gonna make an array wrapper object with methods get,
儲存和追加，這樣攻擊者就無法訪問私有陣列。
store and append, such that an attacker cannot get access to the private array.
所以我們的想法是，我們有一個數組，我們想在一個好的API後面保護它。
So the idea is that we've got an array and we want to protect it behind a good API.
我們希望能夠將其交給第三方，即使是惡意的第三方
And we want to be able to hand it to a third party, even a malicious third
可能想要直接到達陣列的參與方，我們要阻止它。
party that might want to get directly to the array, which we want to prevent.
所以這就是我們要做的事情，
So this is how we would do it,
我們有我們的向量建構函式，它將建立一個向量例項。
we've got our vector constructor, which will make a vector instance.
它將有一個append方法，
And it will have an append method,
它可以用來將東西附加到該祕密陣列上。
which can be used to append things onto that secret array.
它將有一個儲存方法，允許您將資料儲存到陣列中。
It will have a store method, which will allow you to store things into that array.
它將有一個GET方法，
And it will have a get method,
這樣你就可以從那個陣列中檢索東西了，好的。
which will allow you to retrieve things from that array, okay.
所以想一想，你可能會如何實現這樣的事情。
So think about how you might implement something like that.
我要根據我們一直在做的猜測，
I'm going to guess based on what we've been doing,
它可能看起來像這樣。
it might look something like this.
這裡有一個叫做向量的函式。
So here's a function called vector.
我們有一個包含陣列的陣列變數，
We have an array variable containing the array,
這就是我們想要保護的祕密。
that's the secret that we want to protect.
而且它隱藏在函式作用域中，所以我們已經有了一個良好的開端。
And it's hidden in the function scope, so we're already off to a good start.
我們將返回一個包含三個函式的物件。
And we're gonna return an object containing three functions.
我們得到函式、儲存函式和附加函式。
We get function, store function, and append function.
GET函式將接受i並返回i的陣列。
The get function will take i and return arrays of i.
STORE函式將獲取i和v，並將v值儲存到i中。
The store function will take i and v and store into i the v value.
AND APPEND將接受一個值並將該值推入陣列。
And append will take a value and push that value onto the array.
所以我們想要保證的是我們可以把這個給第三方。
So the guarantee that we want to make is that we can give this to a third party.
第三方可以使用這些方法間接訪問陣列，但是
The third party can access the array indirectly using these methods, but
第三方無法直接訪問陣列本身。
the third party cannot get direct access to the array itself.
因為我們希望限制對陣列的訪問，僅限於
Because we want to limit access to the array, to only the things
這是我們可以做的，而不是你可以對陣列做的任何其他事情。
that we can do and not to any of the other things that you could do to an array.
現在事實證明，
Now it turns out,
JavaScript中存在使該保證無效的漏洞。
there is a vulnerability in JavaScript which invalidates that guarantee.
有決心的黑客有可能直接進入陣列。
That it is possible for a determined hacker to get direct access to the array.
現在這個問題已經向世界上一些頂尖的JavaScript專家展示了，
Now this problem has been shown to some of the top JavaScript experts in the world,
他們看不到襲擊。
and they could not see the attack.
這種攻擊不是由於實現中的錯誤造成的，
The attack is not something that's due to bugs in implementations,
所以我們只關心語言的標準行為。
so we're only concerned with standard behavior of the language.
我們知道關於這種語言的一些事情是有問題的。
There are some things about the language which we know are problematic.
例如，您可以轉到Array.Prototype並替換其
For example you can go to array.prototype and replace its
使用您自己的方法推送方法，否則，我們將假定這些問題已經修復。
push method with your own method or, we'll assume that those things have been fixed.
因此，正如我們已經討論過的，我們只關心語言的工作方式。
So we're just concerned with the language as it works, as we've discussed.
因此，您的工作將是找出此程式碼並建議
So your job will be to figure out this code and suggest
如何攻擊程式碼，以及攻擊者如何訪問陣列。
how the code could be attacked, and how an attacker could get access to the array.
然後我們如何修復它，這樣攻擊者就不會那樣做了。
And then how we would repair it so that the attacker couldn't do that.
我的工作就是誠實地回答你們所有關於這個程式碼是如何
And my job will be to honestly answer all of your questions about how this code
好了，你就來了，好嗎？
works, and there you are, okay?